# Axelson Santos, CCNA, MCSA, MCITP, ITIL, CAPM

54 Adrian Street, Moston Manchester, M40 5FG, United Kingdom

Email: axelook@hotmail.com Mobile: +44 (0) 7710629879

#### **PROFILE**

A highly skilled and motivated IT professional, experienced in managing people, mentoring, planning, testing and implementation of high level technical solutions. Fully conversant with the latest IT technologies, with strong analytical, problem solving and communication skills. Committed to maintaining technical excellence by keeping abreast with technological innovations and adapting to changing environments.

## Certifications

CCNA R&S(Cisco Certified Network Associate)

Microsoft Specialist: Windows 7, configuring

Microsoft Certified Solution Associate: Windows Server 2008

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist: Windows Server 2008 AD, Configuration

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist: Windows Server 2008 Network infrastructure,

configuration

Microsoft Certified Professional

MCITP/MCSA

ITIL v2 Foundations

VMware Certified Professional

CAPM

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Microsoft Windows Server 2003/ 2008/ 2012 and 2016 (10 years of daily basis)
- Microsoft Windows 7, 8, 10 (10 years of daily basis)
- Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, Print Server, DC (10 years configuring, troubleshooting and maintaining)
- Microsoft Exchange Server 2003/ 2007/ 2010/ 2016/ o365 (10 years configuring, troubleshooting and maintaining)
- VMware 5/6, Vcenter, Vsphere, Fail over, HA (10 years configuring, maintaining)
- Disaster Recovery, Symantec Backup Exec and Veeam (6 years implementing and daily basis)
- Kaspersky AV, Mcafee AV (8 years implementing and maintaining KAS and EPO)
- Networking Layer2/3
- Security (ASA, Fortigate)

## **EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY**

**Great places Housing Group (Manchester)** 

15.09.2018 -

## **ICT Infrastructure Specialist**

- Support and maintain group and local IT infrastructure (hardware and Software) Servers, Citrix, Lan, Wan, printers, Virtual environment (Vmware)
- Plan and develop DR and Business continuity plan
- 3<sup>rd</sup> party provider management
- Network and infrastructure Management

- Infrastructure documentation /standard operation procedures
- Asset Management
- Help to Redefine IT system strategy
- Risk Management
- Junior Team mentoring
- Budget management/procurement

## Oryxalign (Manchester/UK) 08.01.2018 - 30.08.2018

## **Escalation Engineer /3rd Line Support**

- VMware 4.0-6.5(build, support, troubleshoot) Vrops, Vrealize, Vpshere, Vcenter
- VDI's (Vmware Horizon View and Citrix Xen Desktops)
- Backup and Replication Technologies (Veeam, Symantec Backup exec)
- Exchange Server (2003/2007/2010/2013/2016 and O365)
- Server (DC management/support/AD/DNS/DHCP/GPO/CA)
- Server hardware build (HP/DELL/IBM)
- Networking (Cisco, ASA, Meraki, )
- Security (Web gateway, Web Filter, Antivirus, VPN)
- deliver solutions with both high-availability and proven disaster recovery capabilities
- Project based and 2nd/3rd line BAU functions
- Mentoring and support to 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> line
- Provide Support to Procurement Department
- Onsite Support
- Infrastructure Documentation

# <u>APMTerminals</u> (Angola) 02.02.2015 – to 01.03/2017

## IT Project Manager/ Systems and Infrastructure Lead

- Plan and Develop IT Business Continuity Plan and Disaster Recovery Plan
- Analysing and managing project risk.
- Manage the implementation project and act as main point with thirty party providers
- Develop the training program for IT Team
- Activity and resource planning
- Configuring and design the new Sogester Sites (Luanda, Namibe, Viana, Panguila)
- Design new redundancy links
- Controlling time management
- Design, develop and implement the New Datacenter and new building infrastructure networking
- third party provider Management
- Cost estimating and developing the budget

# <u>APMTerminals</u> (Angola) 01.04.2014 until 02.02.2015 been promoted Systems and Infrastructure Lead

- Manage and develop System Team and infrastructure Team (4 'persons)
- Develop the training program for IT Team (course, exam and mentoring)
- Evaluate new products and manage introductions
- Support and develop internal Helpdesk/servicedesk (11 persons)
- Document all infrastructure and servicedesk
- Provides risk management and quality assurance in the area of activity.
- Licence Management

- Asset Management
- Budget Management for IT department
- Communication Management (Mobile acquisition, Mobile Enterprise Communication Plan)
- Provide Support to Procurement Department
- Manage third party provider
- Define Team KPI/KPO and develop Team Evaluation and appraisal
- Acting as a System Administrator

# <u>APMTerminals</u> (Angola) 15.12.2010 until 01.04.2014 Been Promoted System Administrator

- Manage day to day support tickets
- Support and develop Internal Helpdesk
- Out of Hours Call Out Rota
- Provide mentoring to Support and Engineering Teams
- Evaluate new Products and manage introduction
- Onsite Support and Deployment.
- Document all System infrastructure
- Exchange Implementation and Support
- VMware Implementation from Physical to Virtual
- Datacenter Relocation
- Server administration AD/ DHCP/ DNS/ Terminal Server/ ASA
- Backup Management and tape control
- Antivirus implementation and management
- WSUS management
- Microsoft Server administration (Active Directory)
- Administration and diagnostic skills on Microsoft Exchange Server 2003
- Owning/resolving incidents & problems efficiently within SLAs
- 2nd/3rd line IT support in the area of networks/Cisco switches, Routers, LAN and WAN environments.
- Configure, troubleshoot and control access to local/network printers
- Providing support for pc, printers, scanners, pda and other I.T equipment related
- TCP/IP troubleshooting commands i.e. ping, tracer, ipconfig /release/renew/flushdns/registerdns.
- Installing and configuring network adapters
- Monitoring, configuring & troubleshooting control access to files folders and shared permissions

## Teixeira Duarte Angola 01.10.2008 until 10.12.2010

# Microsoft System Administrator 3<sup>rd</sup> Line Plan & Build Engineering

- •Hands-on experience performing AC and DC power installations
- •Racking and stacking, installation, commissioning and maintenance of Servers and other network equipment

- •Creating rack elevations and other planned/install/as-built documentation for service providers/large enterprise networks
- •Working closely with Project Management and Network Engineers to identify potential problems in advance of network installations, cooling, security/access, rack layout and cable management
- •Liaising with vendors/manufacturers to evaluate new hardware/software and create deployment standards
- •Generating implementation plans and providing technical leadership/guidance during deployment activities
- •Devising own network documentation, updating and maintaining network drawings
- •Manage and administrate: Domain Controller structure Exchange Server structure Domain Name all servers' structures (blade and standalone)- hardware and software all virtualized environment VMWare based.
- •Manage and administrate users & e-mail accounts.
- Manage and administrate the main server room.
- Manage and administrate Web Page and SharePoint Portal .
- Control and supervise the IT security level Windows Updates, Applications Updates, McAfee antivirus updates.
- Control and supervise the IT backup structure, contingency and disaster recovery plans.
- Create and Keep up to date Inventories in the area of activity (User accounts, e-mail accounts, Servers,...)
- •. Create and Keep up to date Inventories for all Software's and IT Licenses.
- Provides risk management and quality assurance in the area of activity.
- •Prepare Internal IT Procedures in the area of activity.
- Create or update IT SOPs in the area of activity.
- Provide regular activity reports .
- Participate and support the IT Manager in all IT Projects in the area of activity.
- Participate in the purchasing process for the IT Dep. in the area of activity.
- Provide necessary support from the area of activity to the IT Team and to the IT Helpdesk Team

## **EDUCATION**

Catholic Business School of Lisbon Postgraduate Business and Management Universidade Piajet Angola BSc (Hons) Computer Network Management (2.2)

### **INTEREST**

Family activities, Photography, Football, Drones.